Meegan Anderson Chicago, IL

630-728-2730 | meegan.r.anderson@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio</u>

Summary of Qualifications

- Full Stack Developer
- 15-year background in Science and Data Analysis
- Enjoys logic, creativity, and problem-solving in building UX-focused applications
- Currently expanding my Front End skills through an internship at Foxtrot
- Certified in Full Stack Web Development from Northwestern University, Chicago, IL

Experience Summary

Foxtrot Chicago, IL 06/2022 - Present

Front End Engineer Intern

Emersed in Foxtrot's existing code base, coordinated with the design team to execute their UX vision, worked with QA for testing, built apps and reusable components for their Next.js eCommerce site, and became a contributing member of the development team Key Accomplishments:

- Quickly got up to speed on a new tech stack and Next.js framework
- Built a Cafe Pickup app for Foxtrot's website to mimic their mobile apps, allowing users to select and pre-pay for items to pick up at their local store
- Built a Wifi Landing Page and Success Page for Foxtrot's website where users can enter their email to connect to the local wifi
- Collaborated with the product design team in an agile environment to ensure the resulting application was within scope while hitting UX design targets
- Worked across multiple teams while learning how to use pair coding and technical sprints to accomplish goals

Northwestern University - Hope Lab Chicago, IL 09/2008 - 06/2022 Laboratory Technologist 3 09/2017 - 06/2022 Senior Laboratory Technologist 09/2008 - 09/2017

Responsibilities: IDL, data analysis, project management, project planning, delegation, safety regulation paperwork and oversight, safety training, protocol training, onboarding of new hires, manuscript writing/editing, purchasing, inventory management, and microbiology experiments Key Accomplishments:

- Promoted from Laboratory Technologist 3 to take on leadership responsibilities
- Author credit on multiple publications in scientific journals
- Consistent Outstanding Annual Reviews

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS/CSS3, JavaScript, SQL(MySQL, NoSQL), and IDL

Libraries: React

Frameworks: Next.js, Node.js, Express, and Mongoose

Software: VSCode, GitHub, GitLab, Figma, Storyboard, GSuite, and Microsoft Office

Leadership Skills

Organization: Task Delegation, Staff Organization, Inventory Management Training: Onboarding, Safety, Protocol Adherence, and Data Analysis

Administration Skills

Manuscripts: Editing and Proofreading Finances: Invoices and Reimbursements

Purchasing: Requesting Quotes and Order Management

Projects Summary

Pick A Flick

https://github.com/NotANewt/pick_a_flick | https://tinyurl.com/mr2hhcsm

- A website to help a group of friends choose a movie to watch together employing user input, anonymous veto, and a final random movie selection
- Tools/Languages Used: React, GraphQL with a Node.js and Express.js server, MongoDB, authentication (JWT), Bcrypt, Bootstrap, CSS, and HTML5

PetLink

https://github.com/GET-POST-malone/PetLink | https://tinyurl.com/42kd8iu9

- An owner-to-owner rehoming pet application where users can search for adoptable pets and add a pet to rehome
- Project Lead: Worked on the JavaScript and handlebars for the Pet Search page, as well
 as organizing and solving issues with routes and general code cleanup throughout the app
- Tools/Languages Used: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bulma, Handlebars.js, and SQL

Tech Talk

https://github.com/NotANewt/tech_blog | https://tinyurl.com/2p8r3cz6

- A CMS-style blog where developers can publish blog posts, view and comment on existing posts, update and delete their posts, and delete comments on their posts
- Tools/Languages Used: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js, and SQL

Education Summary

Northwestern University Chicago, IL Full Stack Web Development Coding Boot Camp

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS

University of Colorado at Boulder Boulder, CO Master of Arts in Biological Anthropology

Field Research for Master's Thesis in Hanoi, Vietnam: Evaluated the variation in cranial anatomy of the cercopithecids in Vietnam. Organized data collection with two undergraduate assistants to take measurements from an extensive collection

University of Notre Dame Notre Dame, IN Bachelor of Science in Environmental Science
A supplemental major in Anthropology